

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

SINHALA

ABOUT ME

I am an experienced frontend developer with over 7 years of software engineering expertise. As a Senior developer in frontend, I have successfully developed the frontend of Lassana.com, the leading e-commerce web app for Lassana Flora (Pvt) Ltd. in Sri Lanka. My skills include proficiency in ReactJS, Redux, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and Java. I excel in translating solutions into code and have a strong track record of working with various APIs and third-party integrations.

EDUCATION

PGDIP, COMPUTER **SCIENCE**

University of Colombo School of Computing / Colombo / 2019

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE

University of Moratuwa / Colombo / 2014

SKILLS

REACT.JS

JAVASCRIPT (PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE)

HYPERTEXT MARKUP LANGUAGE (HTML)

JAVASCRIPT LIBRARIES

3 AVAL

REACT NATIVE

AGILE SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

JAVA (PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE)

SINGLE SIGN-ON (SSO)

ADOBE XD

FIGMA

ANGULARJS

E-COMMERCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

CI/CD

SEARCH ENGINE OPTIMIZATION

DOCKER

KUBERNETICS

LINKS

Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/bhag yadissanayaka/

Website: https://bhagyadev.com/

BHAGYA DISSANAYAKA

- 14, Kaluaggala, Hanwella, Colombo, 10650, Sri Lanka
- +94705127821
- bndissanayaka@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

LASSANA FLORA (PVT) LTD.

Colombo Jan 2023 - Present

Senior Software Engineer (React) (Hybrid)

- Developed responsive and cross-browser websites from referring to UI designs, implementing various functionalities using ReactJS HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Implemented The whole frontend with time span of one year and 9 months.
- Implemented the Shopping cart, SSO login, Delivery process, Category views, Carousels, Menus, Order tracking, Prescription Upload, Money Delivery functionalities.
- Implemented two different views for mobile and desktop.
- This fully responsive app was built using minimum to no media queries.
- Collaborated with design team members, backend engineers and quality assurance engineers to implement new features and improve website functionality.
- Identified and resolved website performance issues to ensure optimal user experience.

LASSANA FLORA (PVT) LTD.

Colombo Mar 2022 - Jan 2023

Software Engineer (React) (Hybrid)

- Created various CSS and JS animations to enhance the user experience.
- Developed responsive and cross-browser pages from concept to deployment using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript and Redux.
- Improved site speed through optimization of images and reduction of HTTP requests.

YOUR WRITER **ACADEMIC CONSULTATION**

Colombo Jun 2020 - Jan 2022

Technical Writer (Remote)

- Part-time technical/assignment writer specializing in Information Technology, Networking, Information Security, Cyber and Network Security, Database Management Systems, International Relations, Research Writing, and Computer Programming.
- Successfully completed Master's and Bachelor's degree assignments with a focus on these subject areas.
- Demonstrated expertise in crafting technical documentation and research papers.
- Developed strong research skills to gather relevant information and ensure accuracy in written materials.
- Utilized strong writing and editing abilities to produce clear, concise, and engaging content. • Adapted writing style to meet the needs of diverse audiences,
- including technical and non-technical readers. • Maintained a strong attention to detail, ensuring accuracy and
- consistency throughout all written materials.

WABTEC CORPORATION

Colombo Jul 2018 - Jan 2020

Software Engineer (On-site)

- Shipxpress was a GE Transportation company and was later merged with Wabtec in February 2019.
- Troubleshooted technical issues in server-side developments involving Java /Spring / Spring MVC / Maven / AngularJS / CouchDB implementations.
- Proficiently collaborated with multinational teams in USA and
- Worked closely with business analysts, development teams and infrastructure specialists to deliver high quality products as a Software Engineer.
- Analyzed proposed technical solutions based on customer requirements, budget and product goal.
- Worked in a Scrum Team and practiced all major scrum ceremonies and followed agile methodologies.

SYNERGEN HEALTH (PVT) LTD. Colombo

Feb 2017 - Mar 2018

Software Engineer (On-site)

- Worked as a backend software engineer (Java/JEE) in two projects, Synergen Billing Interface and SynegenPay Platform.
- Implemented a producer consumer pattern as part of the project implementation. Troubleshooted issues in the code base and fixed bugs reported by QA engineers.
- Used Java, Spring Boot, MongoDB and MySQL.

IFS R & D INTERNATIONAL Colombo

Dec 2014 - Dec 2016

Software Developer (On-site)

- Worked as a software engineer in North America Consulting team providing customizations and maintenance support for IFS ApplicationsTM.
- Received company training on C#, .NET Framework and PLSQL
- Experienced in PLSQL, Centura Job responsibilities included analyze functional specifications, prepare designs and develop customizations, performing technical investigations, installing RND patches and Standard bug fixes, creating and sending deliveries of patches and customizations to customers.

PROJECTS

Mar 2022 - Present

LASSANA.COM

- Lassana.com is the e-commerce web platform for Lassana Flora (Pvt) Ltd. which is a premier e-commerce platform in Sri Lanka.
- This is the cross platform, responsive web site I developed while in employment at Lassana.com. I developed the whole frontend of this application throughout the time span of 1 year and 9 months.